<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS Certified Solutions Architect Course on </title>
    <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AWS Certified Solutions Architect Course on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>01 - Architecture 101</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/01-architecture-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/01-architecture-101/</guid>
      <description>Access Management Basics Shared Reponsibility Model Service Models Availability and Fault Tolerance Scalling Tiered Application Design Encryption  Access Management Basics Principal - A person or application that can make an authenticated or anonymous request to perform an action on a system.
Authentication - The process of authenticating a principal against an identity. This could be via username and passsword or API Keys.
Identity - Objects that require authentication and are authorized to access resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 - AWS Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/02-aws-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/02-aws-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>AWS Accounts  Authentication Authorization Billing  AWS Physical and Networking Layer Well-Architected Framework  Pillars of Well Architected Framework Security Reliability Performance Efficiency Operational Excellence Cost Optimization  Elasticity Introduction to S3 - (Simple Storage Service) Introduction to Cloud Formation  AWS Accounts AWS accounts are more than just a way to log in and access AWS services — they are a crucial AWS feature that AWS solutions architects can use to implement secure and high-performance systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 - Identity and Access Control</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/03-identity_access_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/03-identity_access_control/</guid>
      <description>Identity and Access Control  IAM Essentials IAM Policies IAM Users IAM Groups IAM Access Keys  Multi-Account Management and Organizations  AWS Organizations Role Switching Between Accounts   Identity and Access Control IAM Essentials Identity and Access Management, known as IAM, is one of the key services within AWS. It controls access to the AWS API endpoints that are used by the console UI, command line tools, and any applications wanting to utilize AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 (A) - Compute Services - Server Based</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/04_1-compute_server_based/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/04_1-compute_server_based/</guid>
      <description>Elastic Cloud Compute (EC2) Elastic Block Storage (EBS)  Exam Facts  EBS Snapshots Security Groups Instance Metadata AMI Bootstrap Private Instance and Public Instance Advanced Topics  EC2 Instance Roles EBS Volume and Snapshot Encryption EBS Optimized, Enhanced Networking, and Placement Group EBS optimization Enhanced networking  Cluster, partition, and spread placement groups  EC2 Billing Models - Spot Instances EC2 Billing Models - Reserved Instances Dedicated Hosts   Elastic Cloud Compute (EC2) EC2 is one of the most widely used services within AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 (B) - Compute Services - Serverless</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/04_2-compute_serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/04_2-compute_serverless/</guid>
      <description>Serverless Compute  Lambda Essentials API Gateway Step Functions  Container Based Compute  ECS   Serverless Compute Serverless architecture consists of two main principles, including BaaS (Backend as a Service), which means using third party services where possible rather than running your own. Example include Auth0 or Cognito for authentication and Firebase or DynamoDb for data storage. Servless architecture uses event driven architecture using FaaS (Function as a Service) products to provide application logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 - Networking</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/05-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/05-networking/</guid>
      <description>Networking Fundamentals  OSI Model IP Addressing Subnetting Firewall Proxy Servers  Virtual Private Cloud (VPC)  Virtual Private Cloud (VPC): VPC Routing Routes Bastion Hosts (Jump Boxes)  * Multifactor authentication, ID federation and/or IP blocks.  NAT Gateway Network ACLs VPC Peering VPC Endpoints  Global DNS (Route 53)  Hosted Zone Public Zones Private Zones Routing Policy Simple Routing Failover Routing Weighted Routing Policy Latency Based Routing GeoLocation based Routing   Networking Fundamentals OSI Model The Open Syste Interconnection (OSI) Model is a standard used by networking manufacturers globally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 - Databases</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/07-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/07-databases/</guid>
      <description>SQL - RDS  RDS Backups and Restore RDS Resilency RDS Multi-AZ RDS Read Replica  When would you use RDS Read Replica Deployment   SQL - Aurora  Aurora Serverless  Notes   NoSQL - DynamoDB  Query and Scan Operation Performance and Billing Streams and Triggers DynamoDB Indexes  In-Memory Caching  DynamoDB Accelerator (DAX) Use Case Elastic Cache   SQL - RDS RDS is a Database as a Service (DBaaS) product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 - Hybrid and Scaling</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/08-hybrid-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/08-hybrid-scaling/</guid>
      <description>Load Balancing and Auto Scalling  Elastic Load Balancing (ELB)  Launch Templates and Configurations Auto Scalling Groups  Scaling  VPN and Direct Connect  VPN VPC VPN Components Single Tunnel with Single Customer Gateway Full AWS Resilency with Two Tunnel Endpoint Full High Available VPN Connection Direct Connect (DX) VPN vs Direc Connect or Both VPN Direct Connect Both  Snowball and Snowmobile  Snowball Snowball Edge Snowmobile  Data and DB Migration  Storage Gateway Database Migration Service (DMS)  Identity Federation and SSO  Identity Federation (IDF) SAML 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 - Storage and Content Delivery</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/06-storage_and_content_delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/06-storage_and_content_delivery/</guid>
      <description>S3 Architecture and Features  Permissions Transferring Data to S3 Single PUT Upload (Default) Multi Part Upload Encryption Static Websites and CORS Object Versioning Presigned URL  S3 Performance and Resilience  Storage Tiers / Classes Standard Standard Infrequent Access (Standard - IA) One Zone - IA Glacier Glacier Deep Archive Intellgent Tiering Lifecycle Rules S3 Cross Region Replication  Cloud Front  CloudFront Components Origin Access Identity (OAI)  Network File System  Amazon EFS Throughput modes Performance Mode   S3 Architecture and Features Permissions Bucket authorization within S3 is controlled using Identity Policies on AWS identities, as well as Bucket policies in the form of resource policies on the bucket and bucket or object ACLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 - Application, Analytics, and Operations</title>
      <link>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/09-applicationanalyticsoperations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learn.aayushtuladhar.com/amazon-web-services/aws-solutions-architect/09-applicationanalyticsoperations/</guid>
      <description>Application Integration  Simple Notification Service (SNS) SNS Components  Topic Subscribers Publisher  Simple Queue Service (SQS) Polling Types Elastic Transcoder  Analytics  Athena Elastic MapReduce (EMR) Kinesis and Firehose Kinesis Stream Kinesis Shard Kinesis Data Record Kinesis Firehose Redshift  Logging and Monitoring  CloudWatch CloudWatch Metrics and Alarms CloudWatch Logs CloudTrail VPC Flow Logs  Operations  CloudWatch Events KMS  Deployment  Elastic Beanstalk Deployment Options OpsWorks OpsWorks Components   Application Integration Simple Notification Service (SNS)  SNS is a Publisher / Subscriber based fully managed Regional Service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>